

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Engineering Leader seeking roles in Software Product Development, Software Development, Project Management, Change Management, Requirement Gathering, Application Support, Programming, Apache Tomcat, Spring MVC, JavaScript, Hibernate, Docker, Python, JDBC, SVN, Git



Total Experience: 16 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: MS/MSc(Science) [Computers]

Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Designation: Senior Principal Engineer/Engineering

Manager

Current Company: CATECHNOLOGIES (B ROADCOMINC)

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR,Mumbai,Navi Mumbai

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Maintenance

Role: Product Mgr

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Engineer, Product Manager, Software Product Development, Software Development, Project Management, Change Management, Requirement Gathering, Application Support, Programming, Apache Tomcat, Spring MC. JavaScript, Hibernate, Docker, Python, JDBC, SVN, Git

Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Passionate and energetic hands-on Technical Lead/Engineering Manager with extensive expertise building software products and leading technology innovations in consumer and enterprise markets to develop various web applications on Private and Public Clouds. Able to work as an individual contributor as well as lead cross-global teams and collaborate with companies to develop Saas, web apps and mobile apps. Experience in working in various domains: Continuous Testing, Ecommerce, Device Account and Settings management, Cloud services validation across various mobile carrier networks and regions around the world. Able to use technology experience in Big Data, Analytics, Python, Java, AngularJS, public clouds (GCP, AWS), Analytics, Docker, Kubernetes, NoSQL (Mongodb, Cassandra), Spark.

Work Experience

CA TECHNOLOGIES (B ROADCOM INC) as Senior Principal Engineer/Engineering Manager Jul 2019 to Till Date

Leading team in developing Mcroservices in Python for a production grade Saas Product, used by CA's enterprise customers.

As part of it developing microservices in Python/Flask running on Docker containers in Kubernetes cluster on GCP (Google

Cloud Platform). Also migrated services running on Ws in AWS to Docker containers in GCP. Using Docker and Kubernetes for

deployment, MongoDB for persistence and Flask as the web framework.

SYNTROSYS as VP Of Engineering Oct 2017 to Jun 2019

Managed team of 15 developers in developing various web and mobile apps for Syntrosys's customers. Apps were developed

on Google Cloud Platform (App Engine and Compute Engine). Also involved in Developing a Real Time Analytics system

integrated with EPICS for BARC's nuclear reactors. As part of it also involved in developing a fault tolerant standalone server

from scratch using Mongodb database.

WALMART LABS as Senior Full Stack Engineer Mar 2016 to Sep 2017

Worked as Full Stack Developer for Walmart's supplier centre: https://supplier.walmart.com . As part of it developed RESTful

APIs, rule engine for validating the product information, analytics framework for calculating cycle time, error rates and

1

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld. other

metrics, monitoring and alerts on application failures, moved HTTP based Asynchronous communication to Kafka based

communication. Technologies used in this project are Spring, Kafka, Cassandra, SOLR, Hive, Hadoop, Spark and Java Script.

Implemented Kafka based real time metrics aggregation for Analytics project where collected different metrics to measure

the efficiency of underlying services.

Used Cassandra persist events to track the lifecycle of item that gets setup on walmart.com . Used Cassandra for keeping

state and records of items getting setup through Walmart's supplier center: https://supplier.walmart.com

^ Back to Top

Education

PG: MS/M.Sc(Science) (Computers) from San Francisco State University in 2004

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Java, Python, JavaScript, Shell Scripting			
Visual Studio, STS, Eclipse, MySQL,			
IntelliJ, Netbeans, Cassandra, MongDB			
Jetty, Tomcat, Apache, GIT, SVN			
HTTP, SIP, TCP/IP, Hadoop, Hive			
Mac OSX, Windows, Linux, UNIX			

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.